Graeme Thornber

Mobile: +6421 0292 4529

E-mail: thornberrypie@gmail.com **Website:** www.thornberrypie.com

Summary

I'm a Web Developer and App Engineer with 12 solid years experience building and maintaining web applications in Auckland, Wellington and Germany.

I've worked with some of NZ's top digital and design agencies on many projects and campaigns with local and global clients.

My strongest skills are on the front end, with an advanced knowledge of CMS frameworks. I also play the guitar and am involved in a local theatre group.

Employment History

Full-Stack Developer

DNA Design (2017 - 2018)

Delivering solutions with a senior agile team and creating new features for some of New Zealand's largest public sector clients with Silverstripe CMS. I mainly worked remotely, in constant communication with the team on Slack and Jira, and meeting regularly for events like Codemania and Stripecon.

Lead Developer

Spitfire (2016)

Leading a small team of varying contract developers and designers I directed the development cycle of several projects from initial phases to completion, collaborating closely with clients as well as advising the management team on SEO, web standards and social media marketing.

Freelancer

Thornberrypie.com (2014 - 2015)

After living in Europe I spent some time as a contractor in Auckland gathering more varied skills and honing existing ones while assisting digital agencies to produce solid results in various campaigns and ventures.

Web Entwickler

Scopevisio (2011 - 2013)

In Bonn, Germany I consulted with many areas of the team to completely rebuild the company website from an old Java CMS to Drupal, while working with senior management to construct a Cloud Services company website.

Lead Developer

The Church (2010 - 2011)

Stepping in to relieve one of the founders and lead the direction of development I collaborated closely with some amazing designers to produce some outstanding websites and help solidify the reputation of The Church which still remains today.

Front-End Developer

Solutionists (2008 - 2010)

Under the excellent mentoring of the company founders I fine-tuned the process of converting complex designs into dynamic websites, and over dozens of projects perfected the art of crafting cross-browser CSS and jQuery.

Freelancer

Thornberrypie.com (2007 - 2008)

After gaining a Web Development Diploma in 2006 and some valuable freelancing experience I quickly picked up the tricks of the trade, whilst transitioning from my previous career in hospitality as a waiter and bartender.

Education

2005 – 2006 Natcoll (Auckland, New Zealand)

Diploma in Web Development

1992 – 1996 Howick College (Auckland, New Zealand)

English, Computer Studies, Drama, Music, Japanese

Technical Skills

Expert:

- HTML5 with a focus on SEO & accessibility best practices: WCAG, WAI-ARIA
- CSS3: SASS, LESS, Flexbox, Pure.css, Bootstrap, Foundation, CSS Grid
- Javascript especially jQuery with a variety of libraries, frameworks, APIs and SDKs
- PHP CMS & MVC frameworks: Silverstripe, Wordpress, Drupal, Laravel, Magento
- HTML templating engines: Mustache, Handlebars, Underscore, Twig, Jade, Liquid
- Git management and Agile team workflow: Jira, Slack, SCRUM, Kanban
- Communication: written & spoken, formal & creative, face-to-face & remote

Advanced:

- MySQL, data management, MongoDB, Firebase, PostgreSQL, JSON, XML
- Server administration with Apache & Linux (LAMP), Apache Solr, .htaccess
- APIs & web services: REST, SOAP, Google Maps API, AWS, Rackspace
- CLI tools & compilers: Composer, NPM, Gulp, Grunt, Webpack, Yarn, Babel
- Design tools: Photoshop, Sketch, InVision, InDesign, Illustrator, Fireworks
- HTML4 Email template creation, delivery with Campaign Monitor & MailChimp

Intermediate:

- Modern Javascript: ES6, Node.js, Express, React, AngularJS, GraphQL
- React Native, Xcode, iOS and Android development with Swift and Java
- E-commerce: Shopify, Magento, OSCommerce, Zen Cart, DPS, Paypal
- Testing tools: JSHint, ESLint, CSSLint, Mocha, Jasmine, Jest, Selenium
- Deployment tools: Docker, Capistrano, Codeship, Beanstalk, Beam

Currently learning / very interested in:

- Game development with WebGL, Canvas, Phaser, Babylon.js
- Vue.js, PostGIS and geospatial data mapping, Python, Django, Ruby on Rails

Other Skills & Hobbies

- 20+ years playing guitar: acoustic, electric, bass and other instruments
- Cooking: especially curries, gourmet salads and seafood chowder
- Gaming, fine motor skills, typing speed of 80+ words per minute
- Conversation German and basic Japanese language skills

Examples of my work can be found on my website at: www.thornberrypie.com